# MATTHEW P. MOMJIAN

matthew@momjian.me

Philadelphia, PA https://momjian.me

### STATEMENT OF PURPOSE

I am a 26-year-old striving to further my career in medicine. I have extensive experience in pre-hospital medical care and have proven myself a dedicated student, teacher, and leader with diverse interests and talents. Since completing my bachelor's degree, I have prioritized honing my interpersonal and self-discipline skills and look forward to future growth opportunities. Additionally, providing emergency medical care in a high-volume, urban environment has given me a deeper understanding of modern healthcare challenges. Future goals include practicing as an Emergency Physician in a metropolitan area.

### **EDUCATION**

## ${\bf Delaware\ Technical\ Community\ College},\ post-baccalaure at e\ course work$

2019 - Present

President's List

### Franklin & Marshall College, Bachelor of Arts in Music

2010 - 2014

Cum Laude, Departmental Honors in Music, Honors List (x5), Dean's List, Marshall Fellow Independent Study: "Conducting Performance of Beethoven's Symphony No. 3, Richard Yardumian's Armenian Suite." Adviser: Dr. Brian H. Norcross, DMA

### PROFESSIONAL LICENSES AND TRAINING

Emergency Medical Technician - licensed by Pennsylvania, Delaware, and the National Registry

Bleeding Control Instructor - American College of Surgeons Committee on Trauma

Pre-Hospital Trauma Life Support Instructor – National Association of EMTs

Tactical Combat Casualty Care Instructor - Joint Trauma System, Department of Defense

CPR Instructor and Advanced Cardiac Life Support Provider – American Heart Association

EMS Today Conference & Competition – Journal of Emergency Medical Services

Attended annual industry conference covering innovative pre-hospital medical care.

Competed in EMS skills competition and placed highly multiple times, served as Team Captain.

Resuscitation Academy - Global Resuscitation Alliance

Intensive course focusing on the latest innovations in cardiac arrest treatment and care.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Saint Francis Healthcare, Wilmington, DE

2012 - Present

### Field Training Officer, Emergency Medical Technician III (Senior EMT)

Provide emergency ambulance care in a busy metropolitan system.

Precepted over 20 new EMTs through a three-month field internship program.

Operate as an individual provider in the role of acting supervisor, managing eight units.

Teach annual departmental courses and proctor oral and practical boards.

### **COMMUNITY SERVICE**

### Marple Township Ambulance Corps, Broomall, PA

2011 - Present

### Secretary of the Board, Field Training Officer, Emergency Medical Technician

Volunteer at local ambulance service covering suburban Philadelphia, over 2,500 hours to date.

Work with paramedics providing advanced life support.

Teach public CPR courses as lead instructor, assist with public outreach and education.

### Franklin & Marshall College Emergency Medical Services, Lancaster, PA

2011 - 2014

### Director of Emergency Medical Services, Chief of Operations, EMT

Supervised squad of twenty members and created, proposed, and managed \$25,000 budget.

Coordinated and led education for new and continuing members.

Addressed personnel issues and created member awards to improve retention.

Greater Philadelphia Homeschool Science Fair, Villanova, PA

February 2014 & 2015

Judged various grades at local science fair.

### Armenian Missionary Association of America, Armenia

July 2012

Two-week mission and service trip to rural Armenia. Led religious summer camps and activities.

### Proclamation Presbyterian Church, Dominican Republic

June 2010

Ten-day mission and service trip. Assisted with religious summer camp and provided manual labor.

### HONORS AND AWARDS

### Unit Citation, Saint Francis Healthcare Emergency Medical Services

2018

Given for outstanding patient care during a difficult event in the community.

#### Individual Citation, New Castle County Department of Public Safety

2015 - 2017

Given annually for outstanding patient care resulting in the pre-hospital resuscitation, and eventual neurologically intact discharge, of an individual in cardiac arrest.

### **Exceptional Duty, Marple Township Ambulance Corps**

2015

Given for significant hours dedicated in service to the organization.

### Winner, Pennsylvania Department of Health, HeartRescue Project

2014

Created original video used to educate state EMTs in new "pit crew" resuscitation techniques.

### Unit Citation, Saint Francis Healthcare Emergency Medical Services

2014

Given for outstanding patient care resulting in the pre-hospital resuscitation, and eventual neurologically intact discharge, of an individual in cardiac arrest.

### Nolt Music Award, Franklin & Marshall College

2014

Given by the music department to recognize outstanding students and support original research.

### General Chemistry Award, Franklin & Marshall College

2011

Awarded by the chemistry department to recognize exceptional performance across both semesters.

### Judge's Award and Energy Award, Vex Robotics World Championship

Won award at international robotics team competition.

Future Scientist Award, United States Department of Agriculture

2010

Silver Medal in Behavioral Science, Delaware Valley Science Fair

2010

First Place in Physics, Delaware County Science Fair

2009 2007

Bronze Medal, Delaware Valley Science Fair

2007

Original lab research, attended the International Science and Engineering Fair.

### PRESENTATIONS, RESEARCH, AND TEACHING EXPERIENCE

<b>Research</b> Developed and wrote protocols for fly genetics lab for future biology classes,
--

2012

Franklin & Marshall College Department of Biology.

Presentation "Report on Mission Trip to Armenia," Armenian Martyrs' Congregational Church. 2012

Coaching Robotics Summer Competitions, Broomall, PA. 2008 - 2011

Workshop "Introduction to 3D Rendering with Blender," O'Reilly Open Source Convention.

2010

#### LANGUAGES

Native languages: English, Armenian

### SKILLS, HOBBIES, AND INTERESTS

My travels to over 30 countries have increased my appreciation for many distinct cultures and traditions. I enjoy many outdoor activities such as kayaking, hiking, swimming, and marksmanship. When I am not outside, I have developed skills in computer programming, have competed on robotics teams at an international level, and play multiple musical instruments. As a first generation American and U.S. citizen, my Armenian ethnicity is particularly important to me, and I continuously strive to bring my Armenian culture to my everyday life.